# DANIEL CABALLERO

Mechanical Engineer with a PhD in Computational Mechanics and a passion for Information Technology. I am passionate about learning and applying new technologies to find better solutions for different types of problems. I believe that AI and Big Data represent the future of many disciplines, and I look forward to be a part of that future. I have experience as a CAE Engineer, Project Manager, Programmer, and Data Analyst.



#### CONTACT

Full Name: Daniel Enrique Caballero

Age: 32

From: Argentina

danielcaballero88@gmail.com

+46 764 367 221

Stockholm, Sweden

@danielcaballero88

in Daniel Caballero

#### **SKILLS**

# **Programming Python** Bash C++ **Fortran MATLAB** HTML/CSS **JavaScript** LaTeX **Operating Systems** Linux Windows MacOS **Software & Tools** Visualization (e.g. matplotlib, seaborn, ...) Data handling/analysis (e.g. numpy, scipy, pandas, ...) Git

#### Languages

**Modeling & Simulation** 

(e.g. Ansys Fluent, SolidWorks, ...)

Office

Spanish (native)
English
Portuguese
Italian
Swedish

## **WORK HISTORY**

**10/2020** 

**♥** Wondersign, California, USA

Data Analyst

Clean and normalize big datasets to make them available in production. The process involves writing Python scripts and notebooks for scraping/mining, merging, parsing, re-formating and clustering data.

**1** 04/2016 - 08/2020

GIAC, Mar del Plata, Argentina
 CAE Engineer

Build models and perform simulations in the fields of Computational Fluid Dynamics & Solid Mechanics. Main tools: Ansys Fluent and Simulia Abaqus for simulations; Paraview, MATLAB and Python for Data Analysis & Visualization of results.

**2014 - 2016** 

◆ La Paloma Brewing Mar del Plata. Argentina Sales & Logistics Manager

Multi-role in a growing brewing company. Manage stock and coordinate shipments. Treat with customers and distributors. Assist in project management and production scheduling.

**2012 - 2014** 

Ternium, Buenos Aires, Argentina

Project Engineer

Supervise engineering projects, Design plan of action, write technical specific

Supervise engineering projects. Design plan of action, write technical specifications, draw blue-prints, assign schedule. Coordinate execution, solve emerging problems in-site.

## **EDUCATION**

**2007 - 2012** 

National University of Mar del Plata
 Mechanical Engineering
 Graduated with the best average grade of my class (8.62 / 10), gaining a Distinctive GPA Mention.

**2016 - 2020** 

PhD in Computational Mechanics
Specialized in Finite Element Analysis (FEA) and Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD).

#### **GENERAL SKILLS**

Logical Thinking	Problem Solving	Manageme	ent Cor	nmunication
Multi-Tasking	Research	Documentation	on	Data Mining
Data Management	Data Modeli	ng Data	Analysis	Big Data
Data Visualization	Quantitative Ar	nalysis	gramming	Scripting
Machine Learning Modeling Simulation Python Numpy Scipy				
MATLAB Excel VBA SQL UNIX Ansys SolidWorks				

### **MY TIME**

